here's a visual take on a math fact that
often creates controversy what is the
number 0.9 repeating start with a circle
of Area 1 and take a scaled copy that
has an area of 1 10. then the
surrounding annulus has an area of nine
tenths now we can repeat this process on
the inner circle this time we take one
tenth of one-tenth for the smaller
Circle which leaves us with nine tenths
of one-tenths for the annulus region
which is nine over a hundred imagine
we've repeated this process infinitely
so each time we have a small circle we
take a smaller sub circle of Area 1 10
and shade the annular region of nine
tenths of the previous small circle the
total area shaded is nine tens plus nine
one hundredths plus nine one thousandths
and so on but because the sequence of
radii of the inner circles converges to
zero this means every single point in
the circle except the center point is
contained in one of the annular regions
by the Archimedean principle so the
total shaded area is the area of the
circle which is one but this infinite
sum is precisely 0.9 repeating which
means 0.9 repeating is one